Guide to the Angier Biddle Duke Papers, 1923-1990s and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Pictures Series, ca. 1930s-1990s and n.d.
  - Abukhar, Balenk; J ohn F. Kennedy; Angier Biddle Duke and family
  - Fanfani, Prime Minister of Italy
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., et al.
  - "Duke Farm"
  - Maria-Luisa de Aranha signing wedding registry after marriage to Angier B. Duke
  - Duke, Anthony Drexel and family
  - Duke, Angier Buchanan
  - Estenssero, President of Bolivia
  - Fray, Jacques, et al
  - Princess Grace of Monaco at Flamenco
  - Ambassadors being sworn in
  - Hussein, King of Jordan
  - Roosevelt, Mrs. Franklin Delano, Ambassador. A. B. Duke at swearing-in ceremonies
  - Mwalimu, Julius K. Nyerere, Pres. of Republic of Tanganyika; John F. Kennedy
  - San Martin, Juan Jose Espinosa.
  - Angier Biddle Duke and family, Jimmy Carter, et al. (Box 53)
  - Radio Liberty Committee- Spain (scrapbook)
  - Personal pictures, memorabilia (scrapbook 1943-1944) (Box 54)
  - Visit of the Secretary of Agriculture to Seville; Mrs. Orville (Jane) Freeman; Chas. Nolan Consul General and wife; Douglas Crawford; Agricultural attaché and wife (Box 55)
  - Marilou Duke
  - Official visit of Hon. Sir Abubakar Tafawa Balewa, Prime Minister Federation of Nigeria
  - Wedding scrapbook (names unknown) (Box 55)
  - Negatives (Box 56)
  - Morocco
  - Washington Duke memorial
  - Wyndecote, 1987
  - Kennedy, Jacqueline
  - Nyerere, President of Tangeria
  - Johnson, Mr. and Mrs. Lyndon B.
  - Erhardt, Ludwig
  - Grand Duchess Charlotte of Luxembourg
  - President of Panama R. Chiara
  - Kennedy, John F.
- Appointment Books Series, 1961-1991.
  Bound personal appointment books and social calendars containing minimal entries with names, events, and times. Items occasionally laid in include business cards, brief messages, reminders.
  - Appointment Books, , 1961-1991; (10 folders) (Box 57)
- Subject Files Series, 1960s-1990s
  Created by Angier Biddle Duke, these files represent a broad range of subjects related to his professional activities from the early 1960s to the 1990s. Additional materials on the same subjects can also be found in the Miscellaneous Series.
  - The Spanish Institute, Inc. (Box 58)
  - Foreign Policy Association
  - Moroccan-American Foundation
  - Sheila Isham
  - Resumes of Robin Chandler Duke and Angier Biddle Duke, 1990
  - Long Island University (L. I. U.) Windmill Cartoon, 1988
  - San Ten Karate Association Championship, Glenn Luyjet
  - L. I. U. Sag Harbor Initiative
  - Arthur Ross Foundation, (2 folders)
  - L. I. U. - Rogers Memorial Library, 1987
  - Horticultural Committee, Ellen Samuels, 1988
  - Financial Tap, L. I. C. U.
  - I. U. Community Welcoming Reception, April 18, 1986
  - Long Island University, (3 folders)
  - L. I. U. Development, Major Donor Prospects, 1987
  - L. I. U. Development, 1988
  - Long Island University Chancellor's Award Gala Scholarships, 1986
  - L. I. U. 60th Anniversary Convocation, November, 1986
  - M. M. Anram, MD., Long Island College Hospital
  - Alumni Reunion, 1988
  - 75th Birthday Celebration for A. B. Duke, 1990
  - American Foundation for AIDS Research
  - Nicaragua
  - New Zealand
  - Prodemca
  - Council of American Ambassadors (Box 59)
  - Global Forum
  - For Our Children's Sake Federation
  - L.I.U. Trustees, WAF Council, WPBX Station
  - L.I.U. Planning Committee, Southampton Campus, Council of Overseas, Letters
  - Boys Harbor, Inc.
  - Hill and Knowlton Federation
  - Manaqua Conference-"Reflections on Transition"
  - Council of American Ambassadors, re: Cuba
  - U.S. Observer Report to El Salvador Elections
  - Panama, (2 folders)
  - Panama speech treaties, 12/13 Letters to the Editor
  - Press Release (Nov. 28, 1977)
  - Panama Press Release
  - Democratic House and Senate Council
  - Asian/Pacific American Advisory Council
  - US International Council
  - Resumes
  - St. Paul's School
  - Coalition for a Democratic Majority
  - Duke University- Living History Program
  - Lists
  - Program for New World Anthropology
  - New York State Ethnic Advisory Council
  - Carey Campaign- Ethnic Advisory Council
  - Citizens T.F. Members
  - International Fund for Monuments
  - Council of American Ambassadors
  - Appeal of Conscience Foundation: Grant for Hungarian exchange
  - Adelphi Academy (Box 60)
  - "Ambassadors Abroad"
  - Council of American Ambassadors Metro. Club
  - Council of American Ambassadors
  - Council on Democratic Campaign for House and Senate
  - Dr. Diefenbach
  - Founder's Day- Presbyterian Church, 1986
  - Duke University Jewish Center
  - Foreign Policy Association
  - Buster, Edward W.- Family Counseling Service
  - IRC Delegation to El Salvador Feb.-Mar. 1990
  - Prodemca, (2 folders)
  - Morocco
  - Jay Rutherfurd, 1987
  - El Salvador Elections, Mar. 1989
  - San Salvador, Letter to Editor- Dan's Papers, 1989
  - Joy Silverman
  - Spanish Institute
  - US New Zealand Council
  - Jamestown Foundation
  - Conference on Northern Ireland
  - Armenian Heritage Project, Inc.
  - Global Conference of Spiritual and Parliamentary Leaders, Apr. 1988
  - US-USSR Trade and Investment Institute
  - Humanitarian Foundation for Nicaragua
  - P.A. Wk. 1971
  - Global Forum
  - Western Sahara Mission Report
  - International Rescue Committee
  - National Committee on American Foreign Policy
  - Prospectus- Cold War, Argentina and Spain
  - Freedom House
  - Who's Who
  - Beyond Apollo/Soyuz: Partnership for Progress
  - Institute for Central American Studies
  - Rutherfurd/Duke Audio-Visual Project
  - US Observer Delegation to El Salvador Elections
  - Israel Mission
  - Institute of East/West Business Dynamics
  - New York Dept. of Public Events
  - William C. Bullitt biography, (3 folders) (Box 61)
  - Council of American Ambassadors, (2 folders)
  - Freedom House
  - International Rescue Committee
  - NYC Dept. of Civic Affairs and Public Events, (2 folders)
  - International Rescue Committee 1961-1971 (2 folders), 1972-1973, 1973 (2 folders)
  - Europe-America Conference, (3 folders)
  - Democratic Party Abroad
  - Westminster Board of Trustees
  - Press releases, (2 folders) (Box 62)
  - Fiscal Year Prospectus (1964), White House Executive Office Building, (3 folders)
  - Papers on segregation, (2 folders)
  - Papers on El Salvador, Nicaragua
  - U.S. observer delegation to El Salvador elections
  - U.S.-Japan Foundation, (3 folders)
  - Morocco, (2 folders) (Box 63)
  - Boys Harbor
  - DePeyster, Marilu
  - St. Paul's School
  - Appeal of Conscience Foundation
  - Eaton, William, (2 folders)
  - Carter, Jimmy
  - Humphrey, Hubert
  - Cherne, Leo
  - New York City Democratic Committee
  - C.A.R.E., (2 folders)
  - US-Japan Foundation, (4 folders)
  - NY State Advisory Council on Ethnic Affairs (Box 64)
  - Ditchley Conference on Spain, NATO, and Western Europe
  - International Fund for Monuments
  - L.I.U. Southampton campus
  - Appeal of Conscience Foundation
  - Statue of Liberty- Ellis Island Foundation
  - Moroccan- American Foundation
  - Council of American Ambassadors
  - Spanish Institute
  - Panama Canal Trip
  - Nat. Committee on American Foreign Policy
  - Robin Chandler Duke
  - Middle East Trip
  - Winston Churchill Memorial- Westminster College
  - Palomares nuclear incident
  - Mission to El Salvador- A Freedom House Special Report
  - Democratic House and Senate Council (Mar. 6, 1979)
  - El Salvador Mission (1988)
  - Delegation to the Elections in El Salvador, (2 folders)
  - Guyana Elections Project, (2 folders)
- Audio, Film, and Video Series, 1965-1990s
  Audio reels and cassettes, filmstrips, and video cassettes concerning various major events in A. B. Duke's professional life. Also includes documentary videos, and ceremonies involving other persons.
  [Originals closed to use. A few use copies available and are noted under individual entries; otherwise, staff must arrange to have use copies made before materials can be accessed. Please consult with Research Services staff before coming to use this collection.]
  - OR1. President Lyndon B. Johnson's toast and Ambassador A. B. Duke's response (3/13/65) (audio tape) (Box 65)
  - OR2. Palomares (3/8/66) (audio tape)
  - President Johnson's toast to Ambassador and Mrs. Duke (audio)
  - Angier Biddle Duke, US Ambassador to Madrid (4/18/67) (2 audio tapes)
  - Interview on Pakistani refugees (7/26/71) (audio)
  - Swearing-in: Ambassador Duke- Chief of Protocol (4/1/68) (audio)
  - Jack Valenti press conference (audio)
  - Francis Plimpton Day (audio)
  - "Spain and Europe Today" (audio)
  - Film of ambassador's presentation of credentials
  - Global Forum
  - Global Forum II
  - Prof. Antonio Fontain TV Mon. Switzerland (2 audio tapes)
  - Fontain, Royal Privy Council (audio)
  - Gibraltar (10/26/67) (2 audio tapes)
  - "Celebrate New York" Program Series (10 tapes)
  - Presentation of Henry Morganthau Award to A. B. Duke by Henry Kissinger
  - Under Secretary of State- Economic Affairs Press Conference, Madrid 1966 (audio)
  - 1990 awards dinner
  - "Teenage Mothers: A Global Crisis"
  - People for Mrazek
  - "En Sus Propias Palabras"- Fidel Castro
  - "Morocco Video Showcase"
  - Mac Neil/Lehrer News Hour - Jan. 13, 1992
  - "Decade of Decision" - Population Crisis Committee
  - "Science Held Hostage: RU486 and the Politics of Abortion" (unopened video)
  - "Profile in Excellence"
  - "Sustaining our Planetary Home"
  - Channel 2- "The People, Boys Harbor, Anthony Duke"
  - King Hussein's visit to the U.S. (film)
  - A. B. Duke before the National Democratic Club 6/2/66
- Clippings Series, ca. 1940s-1990s and n.d.
  Large series of clippings and press releases. Subjects include major world events; marriages of A. B. Duke, close family and friends, including Jay Rutherfurd; events related to A. B. Duke's professional life; the nuclear incident at Palomares, Spain; and the death of Maria-Luisa Duke in 1962. Several articles highlight Robin Chandler Duke's life. One folder of materials concerns Doris Duke's death and estate. Only badly deteriorated clippings have been photocopied; the majority are originals.
  Arranged in rough chronological order.
  - 11 folders (Box 66)
  - 17 folders (Box 67)
- Printed Materials, ca. 1950s-1990s and n.d.
  Books, pamphlets, periodicals, articles, minutes, reports of various kinds, printed speeches, leaflets, advertisements, business documents, fiscal analyses, programs, and various other materials. The books cover a wide range of topics: some are texts on foreign policy, diplomacy, and politics, while others (a few novels) seem to have belonged to the private reading libraries of Robin Chandler Duke and A. B. Duke. One book is a limited edition commemorating President Kennedy's inauguration. Other subjects in the Printed Materials Series cover JFK's assassination; Spanish business, trade, and foreign policy; Pakistani refugees; and Denmark. Many of the materials may relate to areas found under the Subject Files Series.
  - 11 folders. Includes "Escape to Freedom: the Story of the International Rescue Committee" by Aaron Levenstein (1983). A. B. Duke played a major role in the efforts of IRC. (Box 68)
  - 11 folders. (Box 69)
  - 1 folder, 9 books, pamphlets (Box 70)
  - 13 folders (Box 71)
  - 4 books (Box 72)
  - 5 folders, pamphlets (Box 73)
  - 4 folders, 4 books (Box 74)
  - 12 folders (Box 75)
- Travel Series, 1965-1990 and n.d.(bulk 1965-1978)
  Routine travel schedules, itineraries, and other records for A. B. Duke and various other people. Series is unarranged.
- Miscellaneous Series, ca. 1950s-1990s and n.d.(bulk 1970s-1990s).
  A wide range of materials not filed under main series, though some related materials may exist here. The most important group of materials in this series may be the writings and speeches of authors other than A. B. Duke. Subjects often include diplomacy and international politics. Includes large groups of invitations and guest lists as well as several memorabilia.
  - Travel files, (10 folders) (Box 76)
  - Miscellaneous (one of these is a classified memo, American embassy in Manila), (5 folders)
  - 17 folders (Box 77)
  - Invitations (9 folders), guest lists (5 folders) (Box 78)
  - 5 folders, Prodemca (1 binder), gold trinket (Box 79)
  - 19 folders (Box 80)
  - 11 folders; includes JFK campaign button. (Box 81)
- Oversize Materials, circa 1928-1983
  - Democratic Nicaragua advertisement (Box 82)
  - Esquire, 1963 Jan.
  - Pabst Blue Ribbon Beer advertisement featuring A. B. Duke and first wife ( circa 1930)
  - Chopin (2 records)
  - 1964 Democratic National Convention Handbook
  - Diario de Colon (2)
  - Certificates and Awards, Spain and other (Box 83)
  - Photographs (Box 83)
  - Certificates and Awards, Spain (Box 84)
  - Appointment proclamation (Box 85)
  - Oversize Printed Materials (one folder) (Box 85)
    Two items: a commemorative publication for John Fitzgerald Kennedy, November, 1963, and a French fashion magazine, 1963.
  - Oversize Clippings ( 1963-1982 and n.d.) (Box 85)
    Roughly 50 items on various subjects. Includes Spanish and Danish periodical clippings and newspaper clippings. Other English-language items refer to the Kennedy family in Spain, and Lynda Johnson's trip to Spain. One lengthier article on radical feminists interviews Josephine Biddle Duke, student activist at Columbia in 1969, and apparently a member of the Duke family.
  - AB Duke photographs (3 folders) (Box 86)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 87)
- Accession (2009-0257), 1961-1980, (1 box)
  Accession (2009-0257) (0.6 lin. ft.; 5 items; dated 1961-1980) consists of 4 For the Record books of speeches and other public remarks given by Duke during his time as Chief of Protocol (1961-1964) and as ambassador to Spain (1965-1967). Also includes a photo album souvenir of his official visit to the Allied Forces of Southern Europe in Naples in 1980.
  - Photo album: Visit to Allied Forces of Southern Europe, Naples, 1980 (Box 1)
  - For the Record volumes
    - Chief of Protocol, 1961-1964 (1 volume)
    - U.S. Ambassador to Spain, 1965-1967 (3 volumes)